Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Kennett Webb Hinks papers, 1953-1963 and undated RL.00710
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Kennett Webb Hinks papers
1953-1963 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.00710
1178
2.4 Linear Feet
Director of Research, Pacific Coast Manager, Manager of Berlin office, account representative, Vice President and Director of J. Walter Thompson Company, 1921-1963. The papers of Kennett Webb Hinks, an executive of the J. Walter Thompson Company, an advertising agency, span the years 1955-1963, and some are undated. The materials consist of copies of Hinks's outgoing office correspondence and memoranda. Letters discuss the planning of advertising campaigns for print, film and radio; market research; product design; selling strategies and advertising techniques; and budgeting. Many include summaries of business meetings. Correspondents include staff members, business associates and clients. The majority of the documents concern Lever Brothers Limited, manufacturer of a variety of soap and bathroom products. Other clients include the Wool Bureau and the New Holland Machine Company. There are frequent communications with other JWT offices in the United States and abroad. A limited amount of material pertains to Hinks's personal, business, and social affairs. Addition focuses on production issues pertaining to the Lever Brothers' Lux Radio and Video Theater program: casting, production services, properties (scripts, adaptations and tie-ins), ratings and reviews, move to a one-hour format, and other issues. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Kennett Webb Hinks papers were transferred to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) in 1987.
Biographical Note
Missing Title
1897 Sept. 3 Born in Mineapolis, Minnesota
1920 Earned Bachelor of Arts degree from the University of Minnesota
1920-1921 Studied law and taught economics at the University of Minnesota
1921-1924 Joined J. Walter Thompson's Chicago Office and served as Director of Research
1925-1929 Appointed Pacific Coast Manager based at JWT's San Francisco Office
1929-1932 Manager of JWT's Berlin Office and supervised Vienna and Warsaw offices
1932-1936 Returned to JWT Chicago as Account Representative for Swift, Elgin and Northern Trust Co. accounts
1936-1942 Elected Vice President of JWT
1942-1945 Served as Lt. Commander, a Member of the Office of Strategic Services Planning Group
1946 Joined JWT's New York Office as an Account Representative
1949 Elected Director of JWT
1952 Elected Director of J. Walter Thompson Ltd. (Canada)
1955 Elected to JWT's Board of Directors Executive Committee
1961 Became a Senior Vice President of JWT
1964 Jan. Retired from JWT
1982 July 22 Died in Baltimore, Maryland
Active in advertising trade association work at his retirement, Hinks was a Director of The Advertising Council. He was a director of the Youth Consultation Service and the Manhattan-Westchester Division of the National Council of Christians and Jews, and a Director and Council Member of the Association for the Aid of Crippled Children.
Collection Overview
The papers of Kennett Webb Hinks, an executive of the J. Walter Thompson Company, an advertising agency, span the years 1955-1963, and some are undated. The materials consist of copies of Hinks's outgoing office correspondence and memoranda. Letters discuss the planning of advertising campaigns for print, film and radio; market research; product design; selling strategies and advertising techniques; and budgeting. Many include summaries of business meetings. Correspondents include staff members, business associates and clients. The majority of the documents concern Lever Brothers Limited, manufacturer of a variety of soap and bathroom products. Other clients include the Wool Bureau and the New Holland Machine Company. There are frequent communications with other JWT offices in the United States and abroad. A limited amount of material pertains to Hinks's personal, business, and social affairs. Addition focuses on production issues pertaining to the Lever Brothers' Lux Radio and Video Theater program: casting, production services, properties (scripts, adaptations and tie-ins), ratings and reviews, move to a one-hour format, and other issues. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising campaigns; Advertising agencies -- New York; Budget in business; Selling; Design, Industrial; Commercial products; Advertising -- Soap; Marketing research; Hinks, Kennett Webb, 1897-1982; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Lever Brothers; New Holland Machine Company; Wool Bureau
- Chronological Files, 1955-1963 and undated; 1
  - Chronological files, 1955-1957; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Chronological files, 1957-1959; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Chronological files, 1959-1962; 9 folders (Box 3)
  - Chronological files, 1962-1963 and undated; 3 folders (Box 4)
- Lux Television (Video) and Radio Theater, 1953-1954; 2
  - Commercials, 1954 (Box 4)
  - John Platt sales managers meeting speech, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Networks: CBS, NBC, 1954 (Box 4)
  - One-hour show--Availability of properties, 1954 (Box 4)
  - One-hour show--Facilities, 1954 (Box 4)
  - One-hour show--Format, 1954; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - One-hour show--Framework proposal, 1954 (Box 4)
  - One-hour show--Meeting agenda, 1954 (Box 4)
  - One-hour show--Planning, 1953 (Box 4)
  - One-hour show--Plans, 1954 (Box 4)
  - One-hour show--Publicity plan, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Plans--Fall, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Properties, 1954; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Properties--Air Force, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Properties--By show, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Properties--Columbia, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Properties--J. Arthur Rank/United Artists, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Properties--MGM, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Properties--Paramount, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Properties--Warner, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Properties and stars, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Publicity, 1954; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Publicity--Plans, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Publicity--Print advertisements, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Ratings, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Ratings--Television, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Report on ratings drop, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Research--Ratings data, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Research--Ratings of Motion Pictures 110 and Over, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Research--Where the TV Sets Are, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Shows--A Place in the Sun, 1953-1954; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Shows--A Place in the Sun--Script, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Shows--Blind Fury, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--Chair for a Lady, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--Christmas in July, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--Gavin's Darling, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--I'll Never Love Again, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--Miracle at the Waldorf, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--Pick of the Litter, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--The Girl Who Couldn't Cry, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--The Outside Witness, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--The Perished Leaves, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--The Pretext, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--The Queen's English, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--The Way I Feel, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--Two Dozen Roses, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--Waiting for Onorio, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shows--Welcome Stranger, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Status report, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Talent--Contracts, etc., 1954; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Talent--Directors, etc., 1954 (Box 6)
  - Teletypes, 1954; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Television, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Television--General data, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Television--Grosse-Krasne (producers), 1954 (Box 6)
  - Television--Studies, 1954 (Box 6)
  - TVR process (television recording for commercials), 1954 (Box 6)